<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Markus van Duijn | Profile</title>
    <link>https://markusvanduijn.nl/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Markus van Duijn | Profile</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 09:30:00 -0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://markusvanduijn.nl/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Don’t Switch Off Your Panels — You’re Missing the Point</title>
      <link>https://markusvanduijn.nl/posts/energy-tariffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 09:30:00 -0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markusvanduijn.nl/posts/energy-tariffs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve come across more and more people saying they won’t install solar panels — or worse, that they’re switching them off — because of the so-called feed-in penalty. And honestly, that frustrates me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not because I think everyone must have solar panels. But because this one change — a small adjustment in how feed-in energy is compensated — is being treated as if it wipes out the entire value of going solar. It doesn’t. Not even close.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Going Solar: A Personal Case for Energy Independence</title>
      <link>https://markusvanduijn.nl/posts/green-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 09:30:00 -0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://markusvanduijn.nl/posts/green-energy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During a recent episode of the Bright podcast, someone said it:
“Solar panels are becoming something for nerds again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you know what? I kind of agree. With net metering being phased out and electricity markets becoming more complex, solar isn’t just plug-and-play anymore. It takes research. Curiosity. A bit of obsession with graphs and peak hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But rather than that turning me off — it’s exactly why I’m continuing to invest. Over the past few years, I’ve gone from hybrid driving to full electric, installed solar panels in 2023, switched to a dynamic energy contract in 2025, and now I’m adding a home battery to the mix.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
